As you've learned in the course
materials, there may be occasions
where you need to work with CSV files.
CSVs are simply files that can be
accessed by other software applications.
So for example, you may have information
in a spreadsheet that you need to
import into a database, and you would
save the Excel spreadsheet as a CSV
file, which would then enable the
database to be able to access it.
Accountancy software is another
example of software that uses CSV
and that can be exported and imported
from Excel and to Excel and from
the software packages that you need.
So just to show an example of
this, I have here a spreadsheet
which is already formatted, I've
just called that CSV example.
But as you can see, this has
a range of formatting applied.
So it has been formatted
and it looks presentable.
If I now go to File and Save As
and then select, rather than an
Excel workbook, if I select a CSV.
So comma delimited.
So that quite simply means that
it is a comma separated value.
And if I save that now and I
then close the example, which
has got the formatting applied.
As you can see, I have two files
now I have the original example,
which was an Excel worksheet.
And this one here, which is the
Excel comma separated value sheet.
So if I double click on that and
open that, you will see that it
has saved it but it has primarily
saved it just the information.
It has took off all of the formatting,
even the columns are now no longer
wide enough to display the information.
So that is what saving as a CSV file does.
It only keeps the information.
An example of this is if I just
close that and just say Save,
if I then go to a Word document.
So if I open Word.
And this will give you a good
example of how it is structured.
If I open the file the CSV
example, you can see that that is
how the document has been saved.
One of the things there is if I actually
made a change in Word, so if I changed
that to 88, and then just saved that.
So once I've saved it, I can close that.
If I then go back to CSV and open the
spreadsheet example, you can see that it
has actually changed the figure in there.
So I can edit it in other software
packages, so I could edit the CSV
file in Word, and then that can
be transferred back into Excel.